Derek Mahon papers, circa 1948-2008
Emory University
- Writings by Derek Mahon, 1976-2007, Series 2; Box 17 - Box 35 (folder 6); OP1-3
  - Scripts and screenplays, Subseries 2.3; Box 26 (folder 7) - Box 31; OP3
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, Act II, Scene 8, TS (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, TS, first rough draft (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, TS, second draft (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, TS, third draft (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, TS, updated 3 December 2002 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, TS, amended 6 December 2002 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, TS, amended 16 May 2003 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, TS, amended 3 June 2003 [includes ALS, 23 January 2004, from Peter Fallon] (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, TS, amended 3 September 2003 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, TS, amended 29 September 2003 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, TS, undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, TS, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, Foreword, TS and proof (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, Introductory Material, TS (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, notes [with TLS, 25 February 2003] (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, proof (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, partial proof and cover [with ALS, 25 February 2004, from Peter Fallon] (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, covers (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, TS of literal translation by Christopher Campbell [with TLS from Jack Bradley, 23 May 2002] (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, research materials (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Cyrano de Bergerac, playreadings, 2003-2004 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - The Demon Lover, "1st draft," corrected typescript (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - The Demon Lover [adaptation of Elizabeth Bowen's short story], TS (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - The Demon Lover, TS (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - The Demon Lover, "final draft," corrected typescript (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Shades of Darkness [re-titled adaptation of Bowen's "The Demon Lover"], working script (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - First Love [adaptation of short story by Ivan Turgenev], corrected typescript (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - The Last Summer [adaptation of Ivan Turgenev's "First Love"], TS, dated 10 June 1982 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - First Love, "penultimate script," corrected typescript (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Gillespie, synopsis and sample, notes on characters and political situation with related correspondence (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - High Time [translation and adaptation of Moliere's The School for Husbands], "1st draft," corrected typescript (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - High Time, "2nd draft," corrected typescript (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - High Time, "penultimate draft," corrected typescript with stage plans (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - High Time, additional drafts, TS (Box 28a, Folder 1)
    - High Time, playbill (Box 28a, Folder 2)
    - "The Living Poet," BBC, November 1982, photocopy (Box 28a, Folder 3)
    - Mary Stuart, incomplete draft [photocopy)] (Box 28a, Folder 4)
    - A Moment of Love [adaptation of Brian Moore's novel The Feast of Lupercal], "1st draft," corrected typescript (Box 28a, Folder 5)
    - A Moment of Love, corrected typescript (Box 28a, Folder 6)
    - A Moment of Love, corrected typescript (Box 28a, Folder 7)
    - A Moment of Love, film treatment with untitled typescript re: The Feast of Lupercal (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - A Moment of Love, screenplay, typescript (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - A Moment of Love, screenplay, typescript with corrections (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - A Moment of Love, screenplay, typescript (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - An Occasion of Sin [adaptation of Story by John Montague] (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Oedipus, MS and TS (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Oedipus, MS and TS [1] (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Oedipus, TS [2] (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Oedipus, TS [with ALS, 19 July 2005, from Peter Fallon] [3] (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Oedipus, TS [4] (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Oedipus, proof [1] (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Oedipus, proof [2] (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Oedipus, Introduction, TS (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Oedipus, cover and jacket copy [with ALS, 15 September 2005, from Peter Fallon] (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - The Opium Eater, photocopied typescript (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Phaedra, "1st draft," notebook (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Phaedra, "2nd draft," typescript with corrections (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Phaedra, "2nd draft," photocopied typescript (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Phaedra, "4th draft," typescript with corrections (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Phaedra, "4th draft," typescript with corrections (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Phaedra, draft, typescript with corrections (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Phaedra, TS (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Phaedra, final (rehearsal) version (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Phaedra, rehearsal version in blue cover (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Phaedra, fragments (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Phaedra, biographical and programme notes (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Phaedra, letter detailing textual emendations (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Phaedra, Lowell jacket cover and Steiner review (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Phaedra, playbill and promotional poster (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Phaedra, promotional poster (Box OP3)
    - Picture of Dorian Gray, typescript with corrections (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Picture of Dorian Gray, typescript with corrections (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Picture of Dorian Gray, assorted pages (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Picture of Dorian Gray, letter and outline (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Pity the Planet [A Protrait of Robert Lowell], corrected typescript with related letter (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Pity the Planet, [A Protrait of Robert Lowell], corrected script (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - "Poet's Choice," photocopy (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - The School for Wives, playbill (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Scratching the Surface, photocopied typescript (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - She Came of Decent People, screenplay, typescript with corrections (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - She Came of Decent People, screenplay (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - The Temptation of Eileen Hughes [adaptation of novel by Brian Moore], corrected typescript [bound] (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - The Temptation of Eileen Hughes, TS, dated 19 December 1983 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - The Temptation of Eileen Hughes, "final version" (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - The Temptation of Eileen Hughes, TS, and other materials (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Threshold, script, photocopied typescript (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Troubles [adaptation of novel by J.G. Farrell], treatment and photocopy of corrected script with memo from David Reid (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Troubles, photocopied typescript (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Works edited by Derek Mahon, Subseries 2.4; Box 32 - Box 33
    - The Craft of Verse: A Yeats Reader, contents for planned collection (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Dylan Thomas, Table of Contents and Introduction, Draft 1, TS and MS (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Dylan Thomas, Table of Contents and Introduction, Draft 2, TS (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Dylan Thomas, Table of Contents and Introduction, TS (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Ireland of the Welcomes (September/October 1996) (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Ireland of the Welcomes (September/October 1996) (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Jonathan Swift: Poems, TS of introduction (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Jonathan Swift: Poems, associated materials (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Jonathan Swift: Poems, Introduction, TS (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Jonathan Swift: Poems, draft of contents (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Jonathan Swift: Poems, proof (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Jonathan Swift: Poems, jacket copy [includes ALS, 14 July 2005] (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Penguin Book of Contemporary Irish Poetry, preface, typescript with corrections (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Penguin Book of Contemporary Irish Poetry, photocopied poems for possible selection (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Penguin Book of Contemporary Irish Poetry, photocopied poems for possible selection (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Penguin Book of Contemporary Irish Poetry, photocopied poems for possible selection (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Penguin Book of Contemporary Irish Poetry, proofs with corrections (file 1 of 2) (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Penguin Book of Contemporary Irish Poetry, proofs with corrections (file 2 of 2) (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Poems / Patrick MacDonogh, MacDonogh Bibliographies (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Poems / Patrick MacDonogh, assorted poems, photocopies (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Poems / Patrick MacDonogh: A Leaf in the Wind, annotated photocopy (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Poems / Patrick MacDonogh: Over the Water and Other Poems (1943) (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Poems / Patrick MacDonogh: "The Vestal Fire," annotated photocopy (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Poems / Patrick MacDonogh: photocopied essays by MacDonogh, including "Poems Marked Urgent" (1945), "Irish Poetry" (1949), "Out of the Night" (1953) (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Poems / Patrick MacDonogh, research materials (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Poems / Patrick MacDonogh, Introduction, TS [1] (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Poems / Patrick MacDonogh, Introduction, TS [2] (Box 33, Folder 14)
    - Poems / Patrick MacDonogh, Introduction, TS [3] [includes ALS, 7 December 2000, from Mahon to Caroline MacDonogh and ALS from Caroline MacDonogh to Mahon] (Box 33, Folder 15)
    - Poems / Patrick MacDonogh, Introduction, TS [4] (Box 33, Folder 16)
    - Poems / Patrick MacDonogh, Introduction, TS [5] (Box 33, Folder 17)
    - Poems / Patrick MacDonogh, Introduction, proof (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Poems / Patrick MacDonogh, Table of Contents, TS (Box 33, Folder 19)
    - Group of photocopied poems with Mahon notes attached (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Interviews with Derek Mahon, Subseries 2.5; Box 34 (folder 13)
    - Notes for BBC Northern Ireland Interview, January 1984 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - "The Watchful Heart" [interview with Derek Mahon], February 1991 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Interview with Derek Mahon [interviewed by Lucy McDiarmid], "unedited draft," n.d. (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Interview with Derek Mahon [interviewed by Lucy McDiarmid], early draft, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Interview with Derek Mahon [interviewed by Lucy McDiarmid], June 1991 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Interview with Derek Mahon [interviewed by Lucy McDiarmid], August 1991 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Paris Review interview [Eamon Grennan], early draft (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Paris Review interview, with edits by DM (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Paris Review interview folders, heavily edited by DM (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Paris Review interview, printed version (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Czech Radio interview n.d. (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Interview notes for "The Book Show" [Douglas Glover] n.d. (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Interview with Derek Mahon [interviewed by Chris Campbell], 2004 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Translations of Derek Mahon's writings, Subseries 2.6; Box 34 (folder 14) - Box 34 (folder 28)
    - "Le Dernier des Rois de Feu" [The Last of the Fire Kings] and "Il ne faut pas s'en faire" [Everything Is Going To Be Alright ], unknown translator (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - "America Deserta" and "À L'Hotel Shelbourne" [At the Shelbourne], translated by Claude Meunier, TS [includes APS from Claude Meunier] (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - "Au-delà de Howth Head" [Beyond Howth Head], translated by Jacques Chuto, TS [includes TLS, 20 January 2002, from Jacques Chuto] (Box 34, Folder 16)
    - "Les Dieux Bannis" [The Banished Gods], translated by Jacques Chuto, TS [includes APS, 28 February 2006, from Chuto] (Box 34, Folder 17)
    - "Ovide Amoureux" [Ovid in Love] and "Les Dieux Bannis" [The Banished Gods], [translated by Jacques Chuto?], TS (Box 34, Folder 18)
    - "Premier Amour" [First Love] and "Reserve d'Oiseaux" [Bird Sanctuary], translated by Jacques Chuto, TS [includes TLS from Chuto, 22 April 2002] (Box 34, Folder 19)
    - "Rock et Rochers" [Rock Music], "La Mansarde" [The Attic], "Ça Va Aller" [Everything Is Going to Be All Right], translated by Jacques Chuto, TS [includes ALS from Jacques Chuto] (Box 34, Folder 20)
    - French translations by Jacques Chuto, 20 June 2002, TS (Box 34, Folder 21)
    - French translations by Jacques Chuto, TS (Box 34, Folder 22)
    - Draft of Denis Rigal's introduction to Veille de Nuit: Choix de Poèmes [anthology of Mahon's poetry] (Box 34, Folder 23)
    - Draft of Veille de Nuit (trans. Denis Rigal and Jacques Chuto) (Box 34, Folder 24)
    - Selection from Poètes d'Irlande du Nord (trans. Jacques Chuto and Colin Meir) (Box 34, Folder 25)
    - La Poesia di Derek Mahon 1960-1990, by Giovanni Pillonca, and Italian translations (Box 34, Folder 26)
    - Italian translations by Roberto Bertoni (Box 34, Folder 27)
    - Bertoni: "I Fantismi, L'Io, Il Mondo, I Libri" [essay] and Italian translation of The Hudson Letter ["Lettera dall'Hudson"] (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - Desk diaries, Subseries 2.7; Box 35
    - 1995 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - 1996 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - 1997 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - 1998 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - 1999 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - 2000 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - 2005 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - 2006 (Box 35, Folder 8)
- Writings by others, Series 3; Box 36 - Box 38a; OP4
  Among Derek Mahon's papers are literary manuscripts of a number of other poets and contemporary writers. Some of these works were sent to him in his capacity as poetry editor for the New Statesman; others were sent for his comments or as tokens of friendship. Among the poets represented are Sara Berkeley, Seamus Heaney, Michael Longley, and John Montague. Of special note is Desmond O'Grady's poem "These Fields in Springtime," which Derek Mahon has substantially revised. These manuscripts are arranged alphabetically by author.
  Arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Allen-Randolph, Jody, "Private Worlds, Public Realities: Eavan Boland's Poetry" (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Alves, Fernando: "Making a Home from Home": A Tradução como espacio de Hospitalidade em Derek Mahon, dissertation, 1999 [includes APS, 22 June 2001, from Alves] (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Asekoff, L.S., Dreams of a Work (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Baltag, Cezar (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Barnes, Dick, "W.R. Rodgers in California" (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Beardsley, Ellen, "Her Heritage" (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Benezet, Mathieu, "Two Poems by Mathieu Benezet" (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Berkeley, Sara, "Patience," "Evidence," "Everyone's Cold," "Man in Balloon," "Undertow," and "Man by His Life" (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Boland, Eavan [interview] (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Cahill, Christopher: Eugene Onegin, TS (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Carson, Ciaran, poems from Poetry Ireland Review 56 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Clifton, Harry, The Desert Route: Selected Poems, 1973-1988 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Clifton, Harry, sleevenote for Claddagh record of Derek Mahon, TS [includes ALS from Clifton, 19 September 2007] (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Cole, William Rossa, "On Ben" (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Cooke, Alistair, "Christmas in Vermont" (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Craig, Patricia, "Belfast: A Compendium" (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Cronin, Vincent: untitled passage on Constantin Brancusi from Paris: City of Light, 1919-1939, TS (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Dawe, "Genesis" (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - De Petris, Carla: "Desmond O'Grady: The Wandering Celt… In Search of Europe," TS (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - Delanty, Greg, American Wake (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - Dodsworth, Martin, "The God of Details" [review of Ted Hughes's Selected Translations and Derek Mahon's Adaptations], TS (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - Enniss, Stephen, "Permanence in Flux: The Poetry of Derek Mahon" [review of Collected Poems and Selected Poems (2000)], TS (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - Ford, Laura: "Minimal Certainties," TS (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - Frazier, Adrian, two chapters from George Moore biography (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - Gibson, Arthur, Lies Bleeding (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - Gordon, Mary, "Reading Auden While Nursing My Daughter," photocopy of setting copy (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - Graves, Robert: "Mid-Winter Waking," MS (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - Grene, Gregory, Quiet Island (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - [Grennan, Eamon], Introduction for Derek Mahon, Paul Durcan, and Paul Muldoon (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Heaney, Seamus: "Anything Can Happen," "Poet to Blacksmith," "Rilke: After the Fire," "Rilke: The Apple Orchard," proof (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Heaney, Seamus, Seeing Things, typescript [photocopy] (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Heaney, Seamus, "The Glamoured" (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Heaney, Seamus, "An Open Letter," photocopied typescript (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Heaney, Seamus, "An Ulster twilight," proof [2 copies] (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Higgins, Aidan, "The Faceless Creator" (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Higgins, Aidan, "Regimented Numbers" [review of Snapshots and Towards a New Novel by Alain Robbe-Grillet], corrected typescript (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Hobsbaum, Philip: "Derek Mahon" [biographical / critical piece for Contemporary Poets], TS [includes ALS, 24 April 2001, from Philip Hobsbaum] (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Hopkin, Allanah, "A Change of Career" (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Hopkin, Allanah, "An Irishwoman's Diary – The Lowry Trek" (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Jonson, Ben: "Hymn to Diana," MS (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - King, Patricia: "'Places Where a Thought Might Grow': The Historical Context of the Poetry of Derek Mahon," Ph.D. dissertation, 1996, TS [1] (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - King, Patricia: "'Places Where a Thought Might Grow': The Historical Context of the Poetry of Derek Mahon," Ph.D. dissertation, 1996, TS [2] (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Larkin, Philip: "For Sidney Bechet," TS (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Longley, Michael: "After Tra-na-rossen," TS [with note from ML, 14 August 2001] (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Longley, Michael, "Baucis and Philemon" (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Longley, Michael, Gorse Fires, typescript with corrections (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Longley, Michael, "Sea Shanty," "Madame Butterfly," "Remembering Carrigskeewaun," "The Shack," "Font," "Northern Lights," "Anticleia," "Blitz," and "Terezin" (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Longley, Michael, "War Sighs: My Adventures in the Second Row" (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Longley, Michael, The Weather in Japan, promotional poster for reading, February 10, 2000 (Box OP4)
  - Lowe, N.F.: "Philip Larkin and LaForgue," TS [includes ALS from Lowe, 15 June 2002] (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - MacLiammoir, Michael, The Picture of Dorian Gray [adaptation] (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - McCabe, Cathal, "Kerkenna" (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - McCabe, Cathal, "A Letter from Lodz" (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - McCormack, Bill, selection of poems (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - McKeown, Susan, selected lyrics (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - Magee, John Gillespie: "High Flight," TS (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - Marian, Dana: "Long-distance Rendezvous (Via Metro-North)," TS (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - Maxton, Hugh, "Bomb Culture" (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - Maxton, Hugh, New Blissful Visions (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Maxton, Hugh, "Post-Modern Elegiac Stanzas" (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Maxton, Hugh, "Swift Mail" (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Merwin, W.S., "A House to the West," setting copy (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Milner, Ruth: "A Thematic Approach in the Exploration of Derek Mahon's Poetry," TS [includes TLS, 13 September 2000, from Ruth Milner] (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Molesworth, Charles, Words to that Effect (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Montague, John, "Brighid O'Neill" and "Fairy Fort" (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Montague, John, "A Devil in the Hills" (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Montague, John, "The Music Box," photocopied typescript (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Muldoon, Paul, "A Clear Signal" (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Murray, Paul, Days and Nights (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - O'Brien, John Maxwell, "Aloysius the Great" (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - O'Donnell, Mary, "On Missing Martin in the Tuileries" (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - O'Donnell, Mary: Poems from an untitled collection [includes ALS, 26 April 2005, and TLS, 9 May 2005, from O'Donnell], TS (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - O'Donnell, Mary: Poems from an untitled collection [includes TLS, 2 April 2006, from O'Donnell], TS (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - O'Grady, Desmond, "These Fields in Springtime," typescript with revisions by Derek Mahon (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - O'Leary, Ronan: Untitled screenplay for Noel Pearson, based on Samuel Beckett by Anthony Cronin, TS (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Paulin, Tom, The Riot Act (a version of Antigone by Sophocles), TS (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - [Rosaleen?], Pat, unidentified typescript (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Rumens, Carol, "A new song," photocopy of proof (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Russell, Peter, "Last Night" (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Shakir al-Sayyab, Badr, "The Book of Job," setting copy (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Sontag, Susan: Lady from the Sea, TS (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Wassell, Elizabeth, Sleight of Hand (Box 38a, Folder 1)
  - Wheatley, David, "Octets" (Box 38a, Folder 2)
  - Wheatley, David, translation of Samuel Beckett's Mirlitonnades, TS [includes ALS from Wheatley, 21 July 2006] (Box 38a, Folder 3)
  - Student papers (Box 38a, Folder 4)
  - Turret poetry poem cards [Knute Skinner, Justin Quinn, Carol Rumens, David Wheatley] (Box 38a, Folder 5)
  - Curriculum Vitae and resumes (Box 38a, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified and miscellaneous (Box 38a, Folder 7)
- Printed material, Series 4; Box 39 - Box 43; OP5-11
  Series 4 consists of collected printed material including printed material by and about Derek Mahon and general printed material that the poet collected. The series includes reviews of his work, promotional material, and several large files of photocopied source material used to prepare a bibliography of Derek Mahon's writing.
  Organized into three subseries: (4.1) Printed material by Derek Mahon, (4.2) Printed material about Derek Mahon, and (4.3) General printed material.
  - Printed material by Derek Mahon, Subseries 4.1; Box 39 - Box 40
    - "Amores IV" and "Noon at St. Michaels" in unidentified source (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - "An Anatomy of Melancholy" [review of Dog Days] in The Irish Times, 7 March 1998 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - "Betjeman in Dublin" in Ireland of the Welcomes, 56.2, March-April 2007 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - "Bohemian Rhapsody" in The Irish Times, June 1, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Bollettario [including poetry by Derek Mahon], 1993 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - "Borgeby-Gard" in The Irish Times, 19 August 2006 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - "Burbles" in The Southern Review, 1995 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - "Calypso" in the Times Literary Supplement, 29 November 2002 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - "Closing down Kinsale," in Image, February 1987 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - "The Cloud Ceiling" in the Times Literary Supplement, 11 March 2005 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - "Coca-Cola" [review of Under the Volcano], in Literary Review, August 1984 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - "Distances" poster [European Poems on the Underground series] (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Dreams in the Mirror [review of Dreams in the Mirror by Richard Kennedy], proofs (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - "Dublin's Shelbourne Hotel" in The Shelbourne [brochure] (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - "Dublin's Shelbourne Hotel" in Ireland of the Welcomes 45.4 (July 1996) (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - "An Empire of Signs" in New Statesman, 9 September 1983 (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - "Euphorion in Ely Place" in Ireland of the Welcomes 46.3 (May 1997) (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - "Fallow Sufferers" [review of Moore's The Untilled Field], TLS, 6 August 1976 (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - Foreword to An Unweaving of Rainbows by John Minihan (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - "Forgotten Poet Is Our Loss" in The Irish Times, 14 July 2001 [extract from Mahon's introduction to Poems / Patrick MacDonogh] (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - "A Ghost at the Gate" [review of Fool's Sanctuary], in The Irish Times, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 21)